Welcome to Mariners Church. I'm so glad that you are with us today. I want to welcome those watching online. I want to welcome those who are with a group of
people for Mariners hosted here. If you have a minute, my name is Eric. I'm the senior pastor here at Mariners. And I
want to celebrate two things before I jump into our study. First, last week across all of our congregations
including Mariners online was really special. We had a rooted celebration and
many of you took rooted online with a rooted group and then at the celebration
we invited people to place their faith in Jesus and 173 people last week
confessed faith in Christ. So beautiful.
And then we had baptisms as well. We had saw 270 people get baptized across all
our congregations throughout Southern California. So last weekend was a major
celebration. I'm really thankful for you who are generous to your church. It's
through your generosity that all of these great things from a human perspective are happening because God
uses your generosity to build his his church and so thank you for being a part. And I also want to say happy
Father's Day to all the dads. I am so proud of you men for being a man who
follows after God because following after him you then are the kind of man
that causes your family to flourish, that your business, your place where you work, that other people are blessed
because you are a man who is being formed into the image of Jesus, becoming
more and more like him. And I know that you know the best way for me to honor
you as a dad, as a father this weekend is to teach the scripture to you because
that's how we grow as men by throwing ourselves into the word. Now that's not
not true for dads and for men, but for all of us and so we're going to continue
in our teaching series this weekend in the book of Numbers.
For many years I was the young leader.
And then I'm not the young leader anymore. You know, you're young and then all of a sudden you're not the young
leader anymore. And in the middle I started when millennials entered the
workforce I was one who believed in the next generation because people have always been believed in me or they gave
me a shot when I was a young leader and so I gave many others a shot and
invested in millennials at both in ministry and in the marketplace. And
then I noticed as I would get close to that generation, the generation right
beneath me, I'm I'm Gen X, that they would sometimes make fun of me in a loving way, but when they got
comfortable around me, they would poke fun at at things that millennials would
poke fun at Gen X for. They would say our jeans were too baggy or that we
overemphasized how tough we were because we rode in the back of a station wagon
without a seatbelt. Um they they would make fun of me when I would call and leave a voicemail like that was breaking
some kind of cardinal rule like you should never leave a voicemail at all.
And so millennials would kind of make fun of me and other leaders in my generation. And then in recent years,
it's been fascinating and a little bit enjoyable to watch Gen Z enter into the
workforce and Gen Z start to poke fun at millennials. It's like the cool kids who
made fun of me getting made fun of is really fascinating to see that that Gen
Z will then make fun of millennials for how tight their pants are. I was made fun of my pants for too baggy. Gen Z
makes fun of millennials for for having too tight of pants, which I kind of agree with to be honest with you, if
you're a dude you can't put your wallet in your back pocket then your pants are too tight. They would make fun of them
for some of the language that they would use like adulting and iconic, lol. I
mean terms like that that Gen Z would would call millennials uncs and so it's
not a good term. It means like uncle like you're too old. And it's just been fascinating to watch. Now sociologists
say that is very normal that every generation rebels a bit against the
generation before them. That there's something inside of us that wants to rebel.
We actually root for rebels. I've seen this in my own life when I will watch a
movie or a television show. I can I can start rooting for the bad guys. When the
the the show Prison Break came out came my wife for one Father's Day got me like
a massive DVD set of Prison Break and we would binge watch it and I found myself
rooting for the people to break out of prison. Now, some of them were wrongly there but not all of them were wrongly
there and I was rooting for all of them to get out of prison. Rooting for the mafia family in a mafia show. Rooting
for Billy Kid in a western. Rooting for the bad guys, for the rebels. What's in
us that is attracted to the rebel a bit.
And I've noticed this even spills out in real life, not just movies and shows.
May of last year, 10 inmates escaped from a prison in New Orleans where I
grew up and they escaped through a a wall where they had taken a toilet out
and they wrote on the wall as they were escaping, "This was too easy. LOL."
Essentially, they were evidently millennial inmates. And so, they escaped through the hole in the wall and they
were on the run. I found myself I I maybe I shouldn't confess this rooting
for them. Just wondering, will they be able to escape? Will they be able to get a new identity? Will they be Will they
get a fresh start? Everybody wants a fresh start. I hope that they get a fresh start. And then I started watching
them online like seeing where they were, how many were getting captured, if they
were still out um if they had not yet been arrested again.
And I realized that the people I were rooting for are people who should not be out on the streets. Murderers and
attempted murderers. Like, what is wrong with me that I'm rooting for these
rebels? The reality is for all of us there is something inside of us that is
going to rebel.
And I'm going to challenge you this weekend in this teaching to rebel in the
right direction.
If it's true, and I believe that it is, that all of us worship something or
someone, that we give our affection to something or someone. If all of us are
worshippers, that means then we're also all of us are rebels.
What we worship, we will then rebel in the opposite direction. We will rebel
against the opposite thing of what it is that we worship. So, I'm going to challenge you to take this rebellion
that all of us have within us and channel it in the right direction. We're going to look at a famous rebellion in
scripture today in the book of Numbers.
We've been walking through this incredible book in the Bible, the book of Numbers. This is God's people in the
wilderness for 40 years. They have been rescued from Egyptian slavery, that's
the book of Exodus. They're going to go into the promised land that God has for them, that's the book of Joshua. In